That's the end of Listening Comprehension.
I've just bought a new blender.
What's that? blender.
You know, a machine that food.
Ah, yes, of course.
The electric kitchen appliance.
Exactly. This one is state of the art.
I've been meaning to buy one for a while, and I did thorough research on which
specific model to get.
I read through maybe hundreds of online user reviews.
Anyway, it's amazing.
Really? What could be so special about it?
I mean, it's just a blender.
Well, basically, it's just a very good one.
It feels heavy and sturdy and well -made.
It also has lots of power and can easily cut and crush practically anything.
This way, the soups and juices I make come out really fine and smooth, with no lumpy
bits. Hmm, I see.
I've never thought of getting one myself.
It sounds like the kind of thing that, for me personally, I would rarely use.
I've never had one before, and now that I do, I use it all the time.
I make a fresh fruit juice in the morning.
Maybe not every morning, but three or four times a week, and it feels fantastic.
It's a really healthy habit.
I can imagine that must feel quite satisfying.
I can picture you getting all creative in the kitchen and trying out a multitude of
different ingredients. And it's obviously going to be healthier than buying packaged
juice from a supermarket.
It's so much healthier.
It's not even close.
Did you know that store -bought juice is like 10 sugar?
Right. So then, you bought it for the health benefits?
Mostly yes. Basically, it allows me to have a more varied diet, with a far wider
assortment of nutrients, because it's not only fruit in my morning juices, you see.
I can also throw in vegetables, nuts, yogurts, cereals, anything that tickles my
fancy. Questions 1 to 4 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 1. What does the man say he did before buying the blender?
Question 2. What does the woman say she has never thought of doing?
Question 3. What does the man say is a really healthy habit?
Question 4. What do we learn about store -bought juice from the conversation?
5. What does the man say he did before buying Thank you for having me.
I'd like to start by stating the obvious.
Berkton has become one of the most popular tourist destinations in the country, and
this has happened under your watch.
Just how did you achieve this?
The achievement belongs to all the residents of Berkton.
It was a shared effort, where everybody pitched in for the communal good.
But how did this change happen?
In about ten years, Berkton has gone from a relatively unheard of, sleepy village to
a must -see destination.
Yes, the change has truly been remarkable.
Berkton was always fortunate to be endowed with such a beautiful natural allure.
The Enbury Hills above the village remain untouched by human development, and the
Sonora Valley just below it is equally stunning.
The transformation commenced in a town hall meeting in Spring 2008, over ten years
ago now, when an overwhelming majority of voted in of Motion 836.
This legislative proposal essentially set out to harmonise the aesthetic appearance
of all the houses in Berkton.
The idea was that if all the properties looked a certain way, with shared design
features, then the village as a whole would look more beautiful.
And it worked.
It certainly did.
I'm looking now at a before and after photo, and the change is truly remarkable.
It's hard to believe it's the same place.
And how do the neighbours feel now?
Great pride, I would say.
But what about the multitudes of visitors now crowding the streets?
Is everyone happy about that?
The tourists we receive are a blessing, as they have completely revitalised our
local economy. Every visitor is warmly welcome.
Questions 5 to 8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5. What is the question the woman asked Mr Grimm after the introduction?
Question 6. What do we learn about Berkton of ten years ago?
Question 7. What resulted from the passing of the legislative proposal, Motion 836?
Question 8. Why does the man say the tourists are a blessing to
Section B Directions In this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then, mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
centre. Passage 1.
Passage Passage Passage 4.
Passage Passage 6.
Passage 9. 10.
Passage Passage Passage 16.
Passage Passage 18.
19. Passage Passage 21.
Passage Passage Passage 27.
Passage Passage 29.
Passage 30. Passage 31.
Passage 32. Passage 33.
37. Question 10.
What did the researchers say about the robot they created?
Question 11. What do the researchers expect their robots to do in the future?
Question What the expect to in
Passage 2. I don't want to boast or anything, but I have always considered myself
something of an elite sleeper.
Given the opportunity, I will sleep for marathon stretches and can doze through the
most extreme situations.
On one very rough ferry crossing on the route to the Isles of for example,
my traveling companion spent the entire three -hour ride throwing up in the bathroom
while I dozed happily on a plastic chair.
Unfortunately, it has come to my attention that I am not an elite sleeper after all.
It seems I am just lazy, because elite sleepers are defined as the approximately 3
of the population who are biologically programmed to need less sleep than the rest
of us. According to a study that came out in March, elite sleepers have rare genetic
changes, which means they can sleep fewer hours than mere mortals without any risk
of cognitive decline.
It may not be possible to change your own genes, but can you train yourself to need
less sleep? Is there a non -biological way to reach elite sleeper status?
I have spent the past year trying to answer that question.
Not for fun, I should add, but because having a baby has severely disrupted my
sleep, for which I still have a great passion.
For a while, I assumed I'd be forced to become one of those people who jump out of
bed at the crack of dawn.
After a year of tough scientific study, however, I have discovered being forced to
get up early in the morning is very different from being an early bird.
Questions 12 -15 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 12. What does a speaker say she did on her ride to the Isles of Silly?
Question 13. What do we learn from the passage about elite sleepers?
Question 14. What has the speaker been trying to find out over the past year?
Question 15. What has the speaker discovered after a year of tough scientific study?
Question 15. study?
Section C. Directions.
this section you will hear three recordings of lectures or talks followed by three
or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
centre. Recording 1.
you read an article about a controversial issue, do you think you'd realise if it
had changed your beliefs?
No one knows your own mind like you do.
It seems obvious that you would know if your beliefs had shifted.
And yet, a new paper in the quarterly journal of Experimental Psychology suggests
that we actually have very poor awareness of our own belief change, meaning that we
will tend to underestimate how much we've been swayed by a convincing article.
The researchers recruited over 200 undergraduates across two studies and focused on
their beliefs about whether physical punishment of kids is an effective form of The
students reported their initial beliefs about whether physical punishment is an
effective way to discipline a child on a scale from 1,
completely disbelieve, to 9, completely believe.
Several weeks later, they were given one of two research -based texts to read.
Each was several pages long and either presented the arguments and data in favour of
physical punishment or against it.
After this, the students answered some questions to test their comprehension and
memory of the text.
Then, the students again scored their belief in whether physical punishment is
effective or not.
Finally, the researchers asked them to recall what their belief had been at the
start of the study.
The students' belief about physical punishment changed when they read a text that
argued against their own initial position.
Crucially, the memory of their initial belief was shifted in the direction of their
new belief. In fact, their memory was closer to their current belief than their
original belief. The more their belief had changed, the larger this memory bias
tended to be, suggesting the students were relying on their current belief to deduce
their initial belief.
The memory bias was unrelated to the measures of how well they'd understood or
recalled the suggesting these factors didn't play a role in memory of initial belief
or awareness of belief change.
The researchers concede that this research was about changes to mostly moderate
beliefs. It's likely the findings would be different in the context of changes to
extreme or deeply held beliefs.
However, our beliefs on most topics are in the moderate range, and as we go about
our daily lives reading informative material, these intriguing findings suggest we
are mostly ignorant of how what we just read has updated and altered our own
position. Question 17.
What happened when the students read a text that argued against their own initial
position? Question 18.
What did the researchers concede concerning their findings?
As the American population grows, so does the number of American moms.
But, more than a century after Mother's Day became an official holiday, even as that
number increases, the share of the American population who are mothers is at the
lowest point in a quarter century.
It's frequently recently noted that fertility rates are falling sharply in richer
countries, but the less observed consequence of this trend is that a decline in
births can also mean a decline in motherhood in general.
According to my analysis of data from the Census Bureau, the decline of American
motherhood is real, occurring very quickly and may continue for some time yet.
Not only are moms making up less of the population, but their characteristics are
changing too, and in a way that might be linked to their proportional decline.
Moms today tend to be older than in the past.
Just looking at recent years, the change in age -specific birth rates has been
drastic. In just the past few years, the peak childbearing age range for American
women has advanced from that of 25 to 29 to that of 30 to 34.
Meanwhile, childbearing among women under 20 has fallen by half or more, while
childbearing among women 35 and older is rising.
One positive consequence of this age shift is that a larger proportion of new
mothers are economically prepared to raise children.
Less positively, however, many women find that, as they age, they can't have as many
kids as they would like.
Plus, having children later in life can increase the risk of health complications.
These finer points aside, one major consequence of the older mom's trend is that
fewer years of a woman's life are spent as a mother.
This means that, at any given time, a larger share of women, and thus of the whole
population, will report not having children in government surveys.
In other words, later motherhood means less motherhood.
Even as motherhood rates decline, Mother's Day, of course, will endure.
In fact, despite the demographic shift, retail spending on the holiday appears to be
rising. It is hard to say if Mother's Day spending is rising more than one would
expect, given that the American population keeps growing.
But one factor might be that the proportion of women who are the mothers of adult
children is rising.
And those adult children may spend more generously when it comes to celebrating the
moms they no longer live with.
Question 20. What does the speaker say is a positive consequence of the age shift in
childbearing? Question 21.
What might be one explanation for the rise in retail spending on Mother's Day?
Recording 3. Since NASA published a paper in 1989 claiming that houseplants can soak
up pollution and toxic chemicals, businesses and homeowners have increasingly
invested in greenery to help clean their air.
But a new analysis suggests it could actually take more than 1,000 plants per square
metre to gain a benefit any greater than simply opening a couple of windows.
The problem lies in the fact that NASA conducted their tests in sealed containers
that do not simulate the conditions in most people's homes or offices.
The space agency was primarily concerned about keeping the air fresh for astronauts
cut off in biospheres or space stations and helping to combat sick -building
syndrome, which had become a problem due to the super -insulated and energy
-efficient offices of the late 1970s.
By the early 1980s, workers regularly complained of skin rashes, sleepiness,
headaches and allergies as they breathed in toxic chemicals from paints and
plastics. NASA found that certain plants could remove chemicals from the air, even
today, garden centres recommend the plants for air -cleaning properties.
However, a new evaluation of dozens of studies spanning 30 years found that
houseplants in a normal environment have little impact.
In fact, natural ventilation is far better at cleaning the air.
The researchers also calculated the clean air delivery rate for plants in the
studies they analysed and found that rate at which plants disperse the compounds was
well below the usual rate of air exchange in a normal building, caused by the
movement of people coming and going, opening doors and windows.
Many of the studies did show a reduction in the concentration of volatile organic
compounds over time, which is likely why people have seized on to praise the air
-purifying virtues of plants.
But the researchers' calculations showed it would take 10 to 1,000 plants per square
metre of floor space to compete with the air -cleaning capacity of a building's air
-handling system, or even just a couple of open windows in a house.
In contrast, NASA's sealed experiment recommended one pot plant per 100 square feet.
This is certainly an example of how scientific findings can be misleading or
misinterpreted over time, but it's also a great example of how scientific research
should continually re -examine and question findings to get closer to the ground
truth of understanding what's actually happening.
Questions 22 to 25 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 22. What does NASA's 1989 paper claim houseplants can do?
Question 23. What is said to be the problem with NASA's study reported in its 1989
paper? Question 24.
What is the finding of a new evaluation of dozens of studies spanning 30 years?
Question 25. What does NASA's sealed experiment recommendation exemplify in
scientists' pursuit of truth?